# Glenn Kirk

114 Creevy Road, Boardmills, Lisburn, BT27 6UW, United Kingdom +44(0)7702574447 • <a href="mailto:terids@gmail.com">terids@gmail.com</a> • Portfolio: <a href="http://terids.rf.gd">http://terids.rf.gd</a>
Available at 2 weeks' notice

## **Background**

A highly motivated individual, dedicated to problem-solving and writing clean and efficient code. I enjoy working on all aspects of game programming, with a focus on gameplay and graphics. I have experimented with most game engines, and have AAA experience with Unreal Engine 4 and Unity 3D.

I have been working on a number of virtual-reality projects over the last year, and have taken a keen interest in the new set of challenges and opportunities it provides to the games industry.

## **Employment History**

Full employment history available upon request

## Freelance VR Programmer (Remote)

(February 2019 – Present)

- Gameplay and graphics programming for a number of clients
- Working with Unreal Engine 4, Unity3D, and Godot game engines
- Working with clients to design and implement core functionality

### Project Lead / VR Programmer / Designer (Remote, Contract), Holonautic

(November 2018 – Feburary 2019)

- Planning the direction and timeline of a new VR project
- Organising a small team by providing a task list of required features
- Setting deadlines and making sure the team met those deadlines
- Gameplay and graphics programming in Unity 3D
- Designing the gameplay, levels, and features

#### Freelance Programmer (Remote)

(May 2018 – November 2018)

- Gameplay and graphics programming for a number of clients
- Working with Unreal Engine 4, Unity3D, and Godot game engines
- Understanding client needs and providing a timely solution

#### Placement Programmer, Sumo Digital Ltd.

(May 2016 – August 2017)

- Developing a AAA console title using Unity3D and Unreal Engine 4.
- Working in a variety of programming disciplines, including gameplay, physics, UI, and audio programming.
- Working closely with the design, art, and audio teams to meet milestone targets

#### **Education**

## University of Central Lancashire

(September 2014 – 2018)

BSc (Hons) Games Development - First-class

## Belfast Metropolitan College

(September 2012 – June 2014)

BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma in Software Development – D\*D\*D\* (Distinction\*)

### **Awards**

2017 Part 1 winner; Part 2 winner (And previous years 2016, 2015)

IBM Master the Mainframe

2015 School Prize for Best Overall Performance in the First Year in Computing

University of Central Lancashire

# **Key Skills**

LANGUAGES Fluent: C++, C#, HLSL/Cg, JSON, Lua, Java

Experience with: C, Assembly, JCL, COBOL, VB.Net, HTML, JavaScript

SOFTWARE Unreal Engine 4, Unity 3D, Perforce, Plastic SCM, Git, Windows/Linux operating

systems, SFML (Library), Direct X, OpenGL, Visual Studio, VSCode

### **Hobbies and Interests**

In my spare time I enjoy tinkering with different game engines, working on my own small projects, and hanging out with my Border Collie pup called 'Pip'. I also enjoy hiking, photography, and sailing.

#### References

References are available upon request.